{
  "a1": "Fighting for the constitution, but having difficulty with our current bureaucracy",
  "a10": "I'm all for free trade if the goods are actually free. It needs to be a reciprocal agreement with these nations that they will not impose undue tariffs on our goods.",
  "a11": "No. The deal cannot fully be verified. Why didn't the United States reach similar deals with Pakistan and India?",
  "a12": "The United States needs to attempt a peaceful halt to the increase of their nuclear program and work with them for mutual understanding and respect.",
  "a2": "I support the current tax cuts and see how they benefit the working poor. I would like to see this become permanent. An action of this type may raise living standards substantially.",
  "a3": "Definitely. Reduce social programs, reduce foreign aid, and military interference in other nations. Cut the size of our military, within reason, and downsize the size of the federal government in general.",
  "a4": "Economic inequality is a major problem. The federal government needs to put more resources into education in order to adequately supply our workforce and elevate the living standard of the lower income citizens.",
  "a5": "The constitution gives every citizen the right to bear arms. The government need not interfere with this unless the gun is used in the commission of a crime.",
  "a6": "Scrap it. Replace it with Medicare for all citizens and double the tax on this.",
  "a7": "State and local governments are better equipped to deal with issues in Baltimore. The federal government doesn't understand the problems faced in this area.",
  "a8": "Do away with capitalism. The competition of such a society leads to stress, obesity, greed, and drug/alcohol related problems.",
  "a9": "We need to remember that America is the great \"melting pot\". We should increase quotas and increase the measures for background checks.",
  "age": 68,
  "background": "Vietnam Veteran, private business for over 40 years",
  "directory": "content/us-house/district-7",
  "district": 7,
  "dob": "06/26/1949",
  "education": "132 credit hours at University of Baltimore, electronic and appliance technical training",
  "filename": "ray-bly.md",
  "full-name": "Ray Bly",
  "jurisdiction": "Howard County",
  "last-name": "Bly",
  "party": "Republican",
  "q1": "How do you assess the Trump administration so far?",
  "q10": "Should the United States continue with the free trade policies it pursued for the last several decades, or should it enact restrictions in an attempt to help domestic industries?",
  "q11": "Do you support the Iran nuclear deal?",
  "q12": "How should the United States address the rise of North Korea’s nuclear program?",
  "q2": "Do you support or oppose the federal tax cuts passed in 2017? What effect do you believe they will have on the economy?",
  "q3": "Is the level of national debt a concern? What, if anything, should be done to reduce it or constrain its increase?",
  "q4": "Is the level of economic inequality in the United States a problem, and if so, what should the federal government do to address it?",
  "q5": "Should federal gun laws be changed, and if so, how?",
  "q6": "What should Congress do with respect to the Affordable Care Act? Should it be strengthened, and if so, how? Should it be scrapped? If so, what if anything should replace it?",
  "q7": "What role should the federal government play in helping cities like Baltimore?",
  "q8": "What can Congress do to address the opioid epidemic?",
  "q9": "What changes if any should Congress make to our immigration and deportation laws and policies?",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How do you assess the Trump administration so far?",
      "answer": "Fighting for the constitution, but having difficulty with our current bureaucracy",
      "shortname": "Trump record"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support or oppose the federal tax cuts passed in 2017? What effect do you believe they will have on the economy?",
      "answer": "I support the current tax cuts and see how they benefit the working poor. I would like to see this become permanent. An action of this type may raise living standards substantially.",
      "shortname": "2017 Tax cuts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is the level of national debt a concern? What, if anything, should be done to reduce it or constrain its increase?",
      "answer": "Definitely. Reduce social programs, reduce foreign aid, and military interference in other nations. Cut the size of our military, within reason, and downsize the size of the federal government in general.",
      "shortname": "National debt"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is the level of economic inequality in the United States a problem, and if so, what should the federal government do to address it?",
      "answer": "Economic inequality is a major problem. The federal government needs to put more resources into education in order to adequately supply our workforce and elevate the living standard of the lower income citizens.",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Should federal gun laws be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "The constitution gives every citizen the right to bear arms. The government need not interfere with this unless the gun is used in the commission of a crime.",
      "shortname": "Gun laws"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should Congress do with respect to the Affordable Care Act? Should it be strengthened, and if so, how? Should it be scrapped? If so, what if anything should replace it?",
      "answer": "Scrap it. Replace it with Medicare for all citizens and double the tax on this.",
      "shortname": "ACA"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the federal government play in helping cities like Baltimore?",
      "answer": "State and local governments are better equipped to deal with issues in Baltimore. The federal government doesn't understand the problems faced in this area.",
      "shortname": "Urban policy"
    },
    {
      "question": "What can Congress do to address the opioid epidemic?",
      "answer": "Do away with capitalism. The competition of such a society leads to stress, obesity, greed, and drug/alcohol related problems.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What changes if any should Congress make to our immigration and deportation laws and policies?",
      "answer": "We need to remember that America is the great \"melting pot\". We should increase quotas and increase the measures for background checks.",
      "shortname": "Immigration"
    },
    {
      "question": "Should the United States continue with the free trade policies it pursued for the last several decades, or should it enact restrictions in an attempt to help domestic industries?",
      "answer": "I'm all for free trade if the goods are actually free. It needs to be a reciprocal agreement with these nations that they will not impose undue tariffs on our goods.",
      "shortname": "Free trade"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the Iran nuclear deal?",
      "answer": "No. The deal cannot fully be verified. Why didn't the United States reach similar deals with Pakistan and India?",
      "shortname": "Iran"
    },
    {
      "question": "How should the United States address the rise of North Korea’s nuclear program?",
      "answer": "The United States needs to attempt a peaceful halt to the increase of their nuclear program and work with them for mutual understanding and respect.",
      "shortname": "North Korea"
    }
  ],
  "race": "us-house",
  "residence": "Jessup",
  "sn1": "Trump record",
  "sn10": "Free trade",
  "sn11": "Iran",
  "sn12": "North Korea",
  "sn2": "2017 Tax cuts",
  "sn3": "National debt",
  "sn4": "Income inequality",
  "sn5": "Gun laws",
  "sn6": "ACA",
  "sn7": "Urban policy",
  "sn8": "Opioids",
  "sn9": "Immigration",
  "social-fb": "profile.php?id=100006636978715",
  "social-tw": "raybly",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "Ray Bly",
  "web": "http://www.raybly.com"
}
